{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Firman","incorrectAnswers":["Yarborough","Tittynope","Funambulist"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'in Turkey and some other Oriental countries, a decree or mandate issued by the sovereign'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"San Diego","incorrectAnswers":["San Francisco","Los Angeles","Sacramento"],"question":"Which California city was a whaling port in the mid-1800s and is located 12 miles north of Mexico?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Dry Ice","incorrectAnswers":["Chloroform","Baking Soda","Epsom salt"],"question":"What is solid carbon dioxide commonly known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kites","incorrectAnswers":["Hot Air Balloons","Starlings","Fireworks"],"question":"What would you expect to see in the skies above the Punjab during the Basant festival, marking the start of spring?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ulaanbaatar","incorrectAnswers":["Skopje","Gitega","Niamey"],"question":"What is the capital city of Mongolia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"My Life As a Man","incorrectAnswers":["The Tin Drum","Breakfast at Tiffany's","The Sound and the Fury"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Nathan Zuckerman'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Brittany","incorrectAnswers":["Provence","Normandy","Corsica"],"question":"What coastal region of France has over 200,000 speakers of a Celtic language?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"gelt","incorrectAnswers":["schmuck","kvetch","mensch"],"question":"What is the Yiddish word for money?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"54","incorrectAnswers":["64","9","16"],"question":"How many colored squares does a Rubiks Cube have?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","incorrectAnswers":["The Fault in Our Stars","Ship of Fools","War and Peace"],"question":"In which book does 'Charles Bingley' appear?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The FIFA World Cup","incorrectAnswers":["The Grand National","The Davis Cup","The Americas Cup"],"question":"Which of these is a Soccer competition?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Cubism","incorrectAnswers":["Baroque","Post Impressionism","Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"The Bathers\" by Paul Cézanne is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Loggia","incorrectAnswers":["Terrace","Gazebo","Patio"],"question":"Which of these architectural features is an outdoor corridor or gallery with a fully covered roof  and an outer wall that is open to the elements?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"When two girls move to the country, they have adventures with the forest spirits who live nearby.","incorrectAnswers":["When a girl is possessed, her mother seeks the help of two priests to save her.","A chaotic clown causes a masked vigilante one of his greatest tests.","A man sees the spotlight turned on him following his wife's disappearance."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie My Neighbour Totoro?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Poland","incorrectAnswers":["Iceland","Macedonia","Slovenia"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Kraków?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mississippi","incorrectAnswers":["Hudson","Ohio","Rio Grande"],"question":"Along which river do the adventures of Tom Sawyer take place?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Iron","Illness","Idle"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter I?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Harp","incorrectAnswers":["Bagpipe","Cowbell","Cornett"],"question":"Which of these is a stringed instrument?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1977","incorrectAnswers":["1972","1982","1987"],"question":"In which year was Star Wars released?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Amman","incorrectAnswers":["Kuwait City","Antalya","Cairo"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Jordan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Penguin","incorrectAnswers":["Stork","Eagle","Swan"],"question":"Which of these birds can swim but not fly?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Paris","incorrectAnswers":["New York","London","Sydney"],"question":"Macaulay Caulkin's folks left him \"Home Alone\" in the original 1990 movie. Where did they go?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1994","incorrectAnswers":["1986","1990","1998"],"question":"Forrest Gump was released in which year?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Europe","incorrectAnswers":["Central America","China","Central Asia"],"question":"Where in the world are parsnips originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Super Mario Bros.","incorrectAnswers":["Zelda","Call of Duty","Halo"],"question":"If you're killing a goomba, what game are you playing?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Senegal","Mali","Chad"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Canelazo","incorrectAnswers":["Kumis","Rakı","Tuba"],"question":"Which of these drinks would you associate with Equador?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Normandy","incorrectAnswers":["Brittany","Alsace","Burgundy"],"question":"Which French region is named after invading Vikings of the mid-9th century?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Parade's End","incorrectAnswers":["Lolita","The English Patient","My Life As a Man"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Christopher Tietjens'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Billy","incorrectAnswers":["A Macho","A Drone","A Ram"],"question":"A male goat is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Holocaust","incorrectAnswers":["Auchterarder","Blitzkrieg","Luftwaffe"],"question":"Which word describes the Nazi genocide of Jews?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"War and Peace","incorrectAnswers":["Doctor Zhivago","Crime and Punishment","The Gambler"],"question":"Which of these famous Russian novels was written by Leo Tolstoy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Moo Shoo","incorrectAnswers":["Kung Pao","General Tso's Chicken","Lo Mein"],"question":"What Chinese dish is traditionally made of shredded pork stir-fried with eggs, bamboo shoots, other vegetables, and served in thin pancakes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Taichung","incorrectAnswers":["Wellington","Busan","Kuala Lumpur"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Taiwan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Marcel Marceau","incorrectAnswers":["Jacques Tati","Charlie Chaplin","Buster Keaton"],"question":"Which legendary mime picked up a 1955 Emmy for Best Specialty Act?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"a more inclusive term for theology","incorrectAnswers":["the history, languages, and cultures of the Indian subcontinent","the Sumerians","crayfish"],"question":"What is Hierology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Judi Dench","incorrectAnswers":["Kathy Bates","Brenda Blethyn","Rachel Griffiths"],"question":"Who won the 1998 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Queen Elizabeth I in Shakespeare in Love?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Well, here's another nice mess you've gotten me into!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"After all, tomorrow is another day!\"","\"Gentlemen, you can't fight in here! This is the War Room!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Sons of the Desert'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"I have had it with these mother—— snakes on this mother—— plane!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Not my tempo.\"","\"Oh, Jerry, don't let's ask for the moon. We have the stars.\"","\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Snakes on a Plane'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Sino-Tibetan","incorrectAnswers":["Turkic","Niger–Congo","Uralic"],"question":"The language 'Wu Chinese' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Charreada","incorrectAnswers":["Bandy","Korfball","Futsal"],"question":"Which of these is a traditional Mexican sport?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Athletics","incorrectAnswers":["Hockey","Table tennis","Gymnastics"],"question":"With which sport is Michael Johnson associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Blur","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Our Lady Peace","Feeder"],"question":"Which English alternative rock band released the studio album 'Think Tank'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Indo-European","Turkic","Dravidian"],"question":"The language 'Sanaani Spoken Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Kobe","incorrectAnswers":["Sapporo","Kyoto","Osaka"],"question":"Which Japanese city is famous for the beef it produces?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The 1990s","incorrectAnswers":["The 1980s","The 2000s","The 1970s"],"question":"In which decade was Hong Kong returned to China?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Swimmer","incorrectAnswers":["The English Patient","Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man","Nine Stories"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Neddy Merrill'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Nero","incorrectAnswers":["Claudius","Augustine","Caligula"],"question":"Which Roman Emperor is said to have fiddled while Rome burned?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"The f in 'fish'","incorrectAnswers":["The d in 'door'","The n in 'no'","The y in 'yellow'"],"question":"In phonetics, which of these is an example of a fricative sound?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Elijah Wood","incorrectAnswers":["Tim Roth","Timothy Spall","Hugo Weaving"],"question":"Which actor has appeared in films including Wilfred and Sin City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"To Kill A Mockingbird","incorrectAnswers":["The Wind in the Willows","The Age of Innocence","Winnie the Pooh"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Atticus Finch'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Nobody makes me bleed my own blood. Nobody!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Are you not entertained?\"","\"I have had it with these mother—— snakes on this mother—— plane!\"","\"What is this? A center for ants? How can we be expected to teach children to learn how to read…if they can’t even fit inside the building?\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dodgeball: A True Underdog Story'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"King Crimson","incorrectAnswers":["Mogwai","Deep Purple","Sade"],"question":"Which British progressive rock band released the album 'In the Court of the Crimson King'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Borneo & Sumatra","incorrectAnswers":["Bali & Lombok","Sulawesi & Java","New Guinea & Komodo"],"question":"Which 2 Islands Are The Natural Habitat Of The Orang-Utan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Austria","incorrectAnswers":["Uzbekistan","Estonia","France"],"question":"In which country would you find the City of Salzburg?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Echo","incorrectAnswers":["Aphrodite","Nemesis","Leto"],"question":"Who according to mythology was a nymph who pined away over Narcissus until only her voice was left?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Kurt Vonnegut","incorrectAnswers":["Vladimir Nabokov","Edgar Allan Poe","Stanisław Lem"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Cat's Cradle'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["China","Southeast Asia","South America"],"question":"From which part of the world does okra originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Brazil","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","Italy","Argentina"],"question":"Which country has won the most FIFA World Cups?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Police","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Wings","Ultravox"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Every Breath You Take'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lewis Carroll","incorrectAnswers":["Enid Blyton","George Orwell","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Hunting of the Snark'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Somalia","incorrectAnswers":["United States of America","Guyana","Mauritius"],"question":"Mogadishu is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Woodwind","incorrectAnswers":["Percussion","Stringed","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument is a piccolo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Police","incorrectAnswers":["Level 42","Wings","Ultravox"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'So Lonely'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"‎‎Edvard Munch","incorrectAnswers":["James Abbott McNeill Whistler","Henri Matisse","Jean-François Millet"],"question":"Which artist painted \"The Scream\"","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Brandenburg ","incorrectAnswers":["Bavaria","Saxony","Bremen"],"question":"Which German federal state surrounds the city of Berlin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Spiders","incorrectAnswers":["Bones","Rheumatic diseases","Buddha"],"question":"What is Arachnology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Clash","incorrectAnswers":["Deep Purple","Feeder","Cheap Trick"],"question":"Which British punk rock band released the album 'London Calling'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Heimdall","incorrectAnswers":["Thor","Ysdragil","Baldur"],"question":"Who is the Norse Watchman of the Gods ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Waitresses","incorrectAnswers":["Haddaway","Spandau Ballet","Right Said Fred"],"question":"Who had a hit in 1982 with I Know What Boys Like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Sawyer, you're going out a youngster, but you've t to come back a star!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Hello, gorgeous.\"","\"You don't understand! I coulda had class. I coulda been a contender. I could've been somebody, instead of a bum, which is what I am.\"","\"I'll get you, my pretty, and your little dog, too!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film '42nd Street'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kangaroo","incorrectAnswers":["Panda","Eagle","Moose"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Qantas logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Sherlock Holmes","incorrectAnswers":["Robert Langdon series","Voyages Extraordinaires","Harry Potter"],"question":"In which book series does 'Dr. John Watson' appear?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Omnipotence","incorrectAnswers":["Omniscience","Omnipresence","Omnivore"],"question":"What is the state or quality of being all-powerful?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Colin Firth","incorrectAnswers":["Javier Bardem","Jeff Bridges","Jesse Eisenberg"],"question":"Who won the 2010 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of King George VI in The King's Speech?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Basoon","incorrectAnswers":["Flute","Clarinet","Piccolo"],"question":"What is the name of the lowest pitched woodwind instrument?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Big Kahuna burger ","incorrectAnswers":["Royale With Cheese ","Dunkin' Donuts","KFC Family Bucket"],"question":"What was Brett's last supper in the film Pulp Fiction?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Christopher Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["Neil Gaiman","J. R. R. Tolkien","J. K. Rowling"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Unfinished Tales'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Scoville scale","incorrectAnswers":["The Heat index","The Shearer Factor","The Spiciness Gauge"],"question":"What is the name of the scale used to measure the heat level of chili peppers?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Claude Monet","incorrectAnswers":["Leonardo da Vinci","Hokusai","Pieter Bruegel the Elder"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Impression, Sunrise\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ben Kingsley","incorrectAnswers":["Dustin Hoffman","Jack Lemmon","Paul Newman"],"question":"Who won the 1982 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Mahatma Gandhi in Gandhi?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Cubism","incorrectAnswers":["post-impressionism","Northern Renaissance","Ukiyo-e"],"question":"The painting \"Guernica\" by ‎Pablo Picasso is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Kangaroo","incorrectAnswers":["Squirrel","Crocodile","Cow"],"question":"A 'Boomer\" Is The Male Of Which Animal?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Underground","incorrectAnswers":["In a tree","Underwater","In a damn"],"question":"Where Does A Gopher Make Its Home?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Oh, Jerry, don't let's ask for the moon. We have the stars.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Stella! Hey, Stella!\"","\"If you build it, he will come.\"","\"You motorboatin’ son of a b****!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Now, Voyager'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Atlanta Hawks","incorrectAnswers":["Atlanta Suns","Atlanta Nationals","Atlanta Rockets"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Atlanta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"pollen","incorrectAnswers":["musical instruments","drugs","study of refuse and trash"],"question":"What is Palynology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Forseti","incorrectAnswers":["Baldur","Thor","Odin"],"question":"Who is the Norse god of justice?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Guns N' Roses","incorrectAnswers":["MercyMe","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American hard rock band released the song 'Welcome to the Jungle'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Thailand","incorrectAnswers":["Uzbekistan","Barbados","The Middle East"],"question":"Pad Thai is a dish that is most associated with which part of the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Kazakhstan","Ghana","Senegal"],"question":"Which of these countries has white on its flag?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New Orleans Saints","incorrectAnswers":["New Orleans Flames","New Orleans Dolphins","New Orleans Cardinals"],"question":"Which of these is an American Football team based in New Orleans?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The records in tree rings","incorrectAnswers":["Muscles","Minerals","Venereal diseases"],"question":"What is dendrochronology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Sterilize them","incorrectAnswers":["Dispose of them","Repair them","Sharpen them"],"question":"What is an autoclave designed to do to surgical instruments in a medical lab?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Marie Antoinette","incorrectAnswers":["Queen Victoria","Abraham Lincoln","Cleopatra"],"question":"Who is reputed to have said said: \"Let them eat cake\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pat Benatar","incorrectAnswers":["Blondie","Patti Smith","Patti Cake$"],"question":"Patricia Andrzejewski Is The Real Name Of Which Singer","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cavatappi","incorrectAnswers":["Orecchiette","Penne","Ravioli"],"question":"Which pasta's name means 'Corkscrews'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Verona","incorrectAnswers":["Venice","Florence","Rome"],"question":"What Italian city is the setting for the opening of 'Romeo & Juliet'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"St. Basil's Cathedral","incorrectAnswers":["Peter and Paul Fortress","Kazan Cathedral","Winter Palace"],"question":"Which of these iconic Russian buildings is located in Moscow?","difficulty":"medium"},